你看到昨天
Did you see that tunic
高级款式课上雅布隆斯基教授
Professor Jablonski was wearing yesterday
-穿的那件束腰外衣了吗  -可不是
- in advanced draping? - I know.
简直就是孤独养猫老太太加大卫·鲍伊[英国音乐人]
It was very "sad cat lady meets David Bowie."
我们就沦落到这个地步了  在垃圾箱里找布料
This is what it's come to -- dumpster-diving to find fabric
准备我们的期中高级女式时装作业
for our midterm haute couture project.
俗话说得好
Well, you know what they say.
一个人的垃圾是另一个人的...
One man's trash is another man's --
-我好像有发现  -我也是
- I think I found something. - Oh! Me too!
卡住了
It's stuck.
因为我们在拽一件东西
That's because we're both tugging on it.
-放手  -我先拿到的
- Let go. - I had it first.
这布料真是要迷死人了
Oh, this fabric is just to die for.
这蕾丝  低切领围
The lace, the decolletage --
你穿一定美极了  必须的
This would look stunning on you -- just stunning.
那个...我...
You know... I...
老妈  你要逼我可爱的未婚妻做什么
Mother, what are you trying to force on my lovely fiance?
我没有啊
No, no, no, no, no.
我只是想向凯瑟琳介绍
I am just trying to expose Katherine
各种美妙绚丽的婚礼杂志
to the glorious world of wedding magazines.
这些杂志都很女性化  有很多痴情新娘
They are all very girly, with a lot of gauzy photos
身着薄纱衣物  目光投向远方的照片
of love-struck brides looKing off into the distance.
或许他们在思考高达50%的离婚率
Perhaps they're contemplating the 50% divorce rate.
不要被这些杂志的梦幻的表面迷惑
You know what, you need to get beyond the fairytale-treacle aspect
要以他们的本质作用看待他们
of these magazines and see them for what they are --
为你筹划婚礼提供思路的源泉
a source of ideas as you plan your wedding.
有道理
Yeah.
看这里
Like this place.
科尔多瓦宅邸
The Cordova House?
标志性的西班牙殖民复兴风格宅邸
Uh, "A landmark Spanish revival mansion
外围还有优雅的停车库
with an elegant carriage-house exterior."
始建于世纪之交
"It was built at the turn of the century,
是建筑美学的永恒遗产
remains an enduring legacy of architectural beauty
就位于曼哈顿中心
in the heart of Manhattan."
我记得这里
I remember the Cordova House.
70年代的时候  那里是一个艺术场馆
It was like a cultural venue for the arts in the '70s.
我好像去哪里参加过一个派对
I think I went to a party there.
不过那是70年代嘛  所以我也拿不准
Of course, it was the '70s, so I can't be sure.
这上面说他们进行了翻修
This says it's been refurbished.
并且开始接受婚礼预定了
And they've started to book weddings.
-我很喜欢  -这里真美
- I love it. - It's gorgeous.
莫非我们偶然找到了一个我们都认同的婚礼场所
Could it be that we've stumbled upon a venue we actually agree on.
是啊  至少我挺喜欢  你呢
Yeah! I mean, I'm good with it. Are you?
不客气
You're welcome.
-谢谢  -对了  谢谢  抱歉
- Ah! Thank you. - Yeah, thank you. Sorry.
我这就打电话问问
I'm gonna make, um... Some inquiries right now.
你得在我们查案的时候打了
Uh, you're gonna have to do it while we're worKing a case.
好的  谢谢  非常感谢
Okay. Thank you. I appreciate it. All right.
看来我们不是唯一读了那篇报道的人
Apparently, we aren't the only ones who read that article.
科尔多瓦宅邸的活动策划人
The event planner at the Cordova House
说他们接到了无数电话
said they've been swamped with calls.
好吧  那他们什么时候有空挡
Okay. When's their next available date?
她说她会给我回音
She said she's gonna call me back.
埃斯波  什么情况
Hey, Espo, what have we got?
两个在垃圾箱里找布料的服装学生发现一具尸体
A body found by two fashion students dumpster-diving for fabric.
被害人名叫艾拉·海因斯  26岁
Victim's name is Ella Hayes. She's 26.
她驾照上写着
According to her driver's license,
她的公寓在布鲁克林
she has an apartment in Brooklyn.
那她怎么跑到制衣区来了
What's she doing down here in the Garment District?
或许是工作上的事
Maybe something work related.
她名片上写着她在《当代时尚》工作
Her business card says that she works for Modern Fashion.
她是主编的助理
She's an assistant to the editor-in-chief.
主编是玛蒂尔达·金
Yeah, that would be Matilda King.
-好吧  -不是吧你
- Okay. - Seriously?
你不知道玛蒂尔达·金吗
You've never heard of Matilda King?
大部分真男人都不知道吧
I'm betting that most real men haven't.
"真男人"是"消息闭塞"的意思吧
Mm, yes, if by "real" you mean "uninformed."
随你怎么说
Whatever.
玛蒂尔达·金是时尚界的传奇人物
Matilda King is a legend in the fashion industry.
或者说是臭名昭著  看你怎么看待她了
Or infamous -- depends on your point of view.
是啊  她的前助理
Yes. Former assistants of hers
曾写书披露她有多难伺候
have written books about how tough she is.
母夜叉  能把人生吞活剥
A dragon lady -- chews people up and spits them out.
她还用勒杀吗
Does she also strangle 'em?
因为蕾妮说死者是死于勒杀
'cause that's how Lanie said our vic died.
早啊  蕾妮
Hey, Lanie.
凶器是一条围巾  还是肩带什么的
So, the murder weapon was a scarf, a sash, or something.
-死亡时间呢  -从尸斑来看
- Okay. When did this happen? - Based on lividity,
是午夜到凌晨两点间
between 12:00 and 2:00 a.m.
我还从她脖子上找到一些蓝色毛发
I also recovered some blue hairs on her neck
是袭击者留下的
left by the attacker.
蓝色毛发
Blue hairs?
那么她是被老太太杀死的
So she was killed by a little old lady?
或者水果姐
Or...Katy Perry.
这是染成蓝色的动物毛发  卡塞尔
Animal hairs that were died blue, Castle.
那就是...苏斯博士笔下的人物
Or... A Dr. Seuss character.
我记得他们不是杀人狂啊
I don't recall any of them being homicidal.
是啊  我得再想个理论
That's true. I need a new theory.
我有
Well, I've got one.
凶手很强壮
Our killer was strong.
能把尸体抬起来扔进垃圾箱
And he or she was able to lift the body into the dumpster.
埃斯波  让警员盘查这一带  寻找目击者
Espo, can you get uniforms to canvass the area for any witnesses?
我和卡塞尔去她单位
Castle and I will go to her work.
你和莱恩去她家
You and Ryan head off to her place --
看看那儿有没有什么线索能告诉我们
see if there's anything there that'll indicate
-她昨晚为什么会来这儿  -好的
- why she was here last night. - Right on.
我和艾拉一起上的帕森学院
Ella and I went to Parsons together.
我们做了两年室友了
And then we've been roommates for the past two years.
我还是难以相信
I still can't believe this.
你最后见到她是什么时候
When was the last time you saw her?
昨天早上
Yesterday morning.
她像往常一样五点起床  然后出门
She was up at 5:00, like always, and then out the door
上班路上还要给玛蒂尔达买咖啡和蔓越橘烤饼
to get Matilda's coffee and cranberry scone on her way to the office.
下班后呢  你看到她了吗
What about after work -- did you see her then?
没  我是萨克斯百货的采购员  总是很晚回家
No. I'm a buyer at Saks, so I don't get home till late.
艾拉有男友  或者情人什么的吗
Did Ella have a boyfriend or a relationship?
没有
No.
她要全天为玛蒂尔达待命
She was on call for Matilda 24/7,
所以根本没时间经营感情
so she didn't have time for relationships...
和她真正想做的事
Or for the one thing that she really wanted to do.
-什么事  -设计服装
- Which was what? - Design.
她本期望在《当代时尚》工作能给她更多机会
She hoped working at Modern Fashion would open doors for her.
据你所知  艾拉遇到什么麻烦了吗
Was Ella having any problems that you know of?
她最近压力很大
Um... She had been stressed lately,
比平时的压力还大
a little more than usual.
我问她时  她只说是工作上的事  没详说
I asked her. She said it was work, but she didn't go into details.
莉莉安  如果可以的话
Lilian, if you don't mind,
我想找个警官过来给你做笔录
I'd like to have an officer come by and take your statement.
当然  我会尽力帮忙
Of course. Anything I can do to help.
我们这里没有信号
Oh, we don't get cell reception in here.
-用我的座机吧  -谢谢
- You can use my landline if you like. - Thanks.
这是我的名片
Here's my card.
如果你又记起了什么  请给我打电话
If you can remember anything else, please give me a call, okay?
好  谢谢
Yeah. Thank you.
我们到了
Well, this is it --
时尚界的职业联盟
The big leagues for anyone who wants to work in fashion.
看来要在这儿工作都必须是辣妹
Wow. Apparently, you have to be a total hottie just to work here.
我是以一个完全不在乎这一切的
And I'm saying that as a completely detached,
准新郎的身份说这话的
soon-to-be-married observer.
-没事  卡塞尔  看吧  -真的吗
- It's okay, Castle. Stare all you want. - Really?
不行  不过想不看都难
Actually, no. But it's kind of hard not to.
玛蒂尔达只雇那些
I mean, Matilda only hires people
符合杂志风格的人  你必须看上去像那么回事
that fit the magazine's brand. You have to...Look the part.
你对玛蒂尔达·金似乎很了解啊
You seem to know a lot about Matilda King.
总会听到些传闻嘛
Yeah, well, I've picked up a thing or two.
你好  纽约警察  我们要找玛蒂尔达·金
Hi. NYPD. We need to speak with Matilda King.
你预约了吗
Do you have an appointment?
你没听清她是警察吧
D-- oh, I think you missed the part about the NYPD.
拜托
Please.
我今天早上才刚刚接管这份工作
I just took over this desk, this morning.
如果我把你加入她的日程她会发疯的
She's going to freak out if I add you to the schedule.
你们知道之前的那个助理有多惨吗
Do you have any idea what happened to the last assistant?
知道  她死了
Yes. She's dead.
死了  什么意思
Dead? What do you mean?
-不行  -天呐  她来了
- No, no, no, no. - Oh, God. Here she comes.
我绝不接受拒绝
I won't take no for an answer.
你必须一起上游艇
You must join us on the yacht.
乔治会展出他的新作品
Giorgio will show his new collection.
戈登·拉姆齐下厨
Gordon Ramsay is cooking.
Lady Gaga要来表演
Lady Gaga is performing.
再次推动时尚的极限
Pushing the boundaries of style --
不过当然是往错误的方向推动
No doubt, in the wrong direction.
给我回话哦
So, let me know.
-你是新助理  -我叫凯莉
- New assistant. - It's Carrie.
你要是合格了我会记住你的名字的  给
I'll learn your name when you've earned it. Here.
这些是给你的留言
Oh, uh, these are your messages,
朱利安·布鲁克纳在你办公室等你
and Julian Bruckner is waiting in your office.
这是谁
And who is this?
纽约警察
Uh...NYPD.
我们要问你几个问题金女士
We need to ask you a few questions, Ms. King.
凯特·贝克特
Kate Beckett?
我一直忘不掉那对颧骨
I never could forget those cheekbones.
你们认识
Uh, what -- you two know each other?
是啊
Uh...Yeah. Yeah.
我做模特时认识的  不过只做了很短的时间
When I was a model... for about 15 minutes.
你为《当代时尚》做过模特
You modeled for Modern Fashion?
我提出在99年1月的期刊上给她一个位置
I offered her a spread in the January '99 issue.
那一期封面是妮可·基德曼
Nicole Kidman was on the cover.
你却拒绝了
And you passed.
直至今日  你还是唯一拒绝我的人
To date, you're the only person to ever tell me no.
我现在忙得很
I'm wall-to-wall.
我们再约吧
We'll have to reschedule.
你又要遭到顶撞了
Uh, get ready to be told no again.
我们要问你几个问题
We need to ask you a few questions
是关于你的助理  艾拉·海因斯
about your assistant, Ella Hayes.
而且等不得
It cannot wait.
去我办公室谈吧  电话不要接进来
We'll talk in my office. Hold my calls.
对了  艾拉是前助理了
By the way, Ella is my former assistant.
稍等一下  朱利安
Be right with you, Julian.
你说前助理是什么意思
Uh, so, what do you mean by "former"?
我昨天下午炒掉了她
I fired her yesterday afternoon,
她的日程安排错了
after she made a scheduling mistake
害我晚到了一个董事会议
and I showed up to a board meeting late.
她上周还犯过类似错误
And that was after her mistake last week,
结果我让杂志的新东家等了我45分钟
when I kept the new owner of our magazine waiting for 45 minutes.
玛蒂尔达  你看到"美妙五人"摄影的校样了吗
Matilda, have you seen the proofs from the "Fab Five" photo shoot?
真是美极了
They are divine.
希望如此  朱利安
They'd better be, Julian.
你目前拿给我的东西可都不怎么样
So far, everything you've submitted has been rather distrait.
玛蒂尔达这些设计师都还乳臭未干
Oh, Matilda, these designers are barely out of diapers.
抱歉  打扰一下
E-excuse me. Sorry.
我们在调查凶杀案
We're investigating a murder here.
凶杀
Murder?
谁死了
Of whom?
你的前助理艾拉
Your former assistant, Ella.
艾拉死了  怎么死的
El-- Ella's dead? How?
我们也想搞清楚
That's what we're trying to figure out.
你们知道她有什么麻烦吗
Now, do you know if she had any problems?
这不会跟她和格蕾丝的事有关吧
You don't think this had anything to do with that incident with Grace?
什么事
What incident?
谁是格蕾丝
And who's Grace?
格蕾丝是我另一个助理  也被我炒了
Grace is my other assistant, whom I fired
因为她没有及时纠正日程安排的错误
because she allowed the scheduling mistakes to happen.
那她俩之间有什么事
And what was the incident?
昨天艾拉和格蕾丝
Well, apparently, yesterday, when Ella and Grace
由保安护送离开的时候
were escorted out of the building by security,
大打出手
they literally got into a brawl,
就在摄影现场
right in the middle of a photo shoot.
摄影师塞奇不得不出手阻止
The photographer, Serge, had to break it up.
是啊  她俩真的是大动干戈
Yeah. The two of them really went at it.
牟足了力气的小妞大战
I mean, it was a full-on catfight.
还挺性感的
It was actually kind of sexy.
她俩为什么打架
What exactly was the fight about?
为了工作
It was about the job. Okay?
我听到格蕾丝怪艾拉害她丢了饭碗
I overheard Grace blame Ella for -- for getting her fired.
塞奇
Serge!
还要多久
How long will this take?
我完成设计的最后期限就要到了
I'm up against a deadline to finish my design.
为了取悦玛蒂尔达  你就在这儿等着吧
You'll be here as long as it takes to make Matilda happy.
我们都要遵从的咒语
The mantra we all live by.
关于那场打斗你还记得其它细节吗
Uh, did you remember any other details about the fight?
不止记得  我可以给你们看
I can do better than that. I can show you something.
我当时在摄影
I was shooting at the time.
拍到了几张她们出现在背景里的照片
And got a few frames with them in the background.
就这儿  看吧
There. Check it out.
能放大她俩吗
Can...you zoom in on that?
能
Sure.
看格蕾丝的围巾
Check out Grace's scarf.
蕾妮说艾拉是被勒杀
Lanie said she found blue hairs
且在颈部发现了蓝色毛发
on Ella's neck from being strangled.
看来格蕾丝穿着杀人装束
Looks like Grace was dressed to kill.
我从小看着《当代时尚》长大的
Look, I grew up reading Modern Fashion.
为玛蒂尔达·金工作简直是我的梦想
Working for Matilda King, that was my dream.
被玛蒂尔达解雇的人  圈内都记得
But when Matilda fires someone, people remember,
也就是说我在时尚圈基本混不下去了
which means my career in fashion is pretty much done,
多亏了艾拉
thanks to Ella.
你认为你被炒是她的错
Because you believed it was her fault that you got fired.
就是她的错
It was her fault.
她之所以会犯错  是因为她忙于
She started making mistakes because she was so busy
拍优美那种设计师的马屁
sucking up to designers like Yumi
还有炫耀她的草图  却害我付出了代价
and showing off her sketches, and I paid the price.
所以你杀了她
Which is why you killed her.
你到底在说什么
What are you even talking about?
我俩打了一架  就这样而已
We got in a fight. That was it.
好吧  那解释一下这个
Okay, okay. Then explain this.
这条蓝色羊驼毛围巾是在你公寓里找到的
This blue alpaca scarf was found at your apartment.
跟艾拉被勒死后
It's an exact match to the hairs
颈部残留的毛发完全匹配
found on ella's neck after she was strangled.
拜托  这围巾又不止我一个人有
Come on. Other people have that scarf.
是的  但就你有杀人动机
Yeah, but you're the only one with motive.
这围巾是《当代时尚》送的圣诞礼物
It was the Christmas gift from Modern Fashion.
每个人都有
We all got the scarf.
也许艾拉当时正围着  凶手就用来勒死了她
Maybe Ella was wearing hers and someone choked her with it.
你凌晨12点到2点在哪  格蕾丝
Where were you between 12:00 and 2:00 a.m., Grace?
我刚被炒鱿鱼
I'd just gotten fired.
几个朋友带我出去喝酒了
Some friends took me out and got me drunk.
-你可以问他们  -我会的
- You can ask them. - I will.
同时  我们再说说艾拉的事
In the meantime, let's talk about Ella.
她室友觉得她最近工作上有点麻烦
Her roommate thought that she was having trouble at the office.
你跟她共事  知道是什么麻烦吗
You worked with her. You know what it was?
好像是有点事
Actually, there was something else.
几天前  午餐时间
A few days ago, at lunchtime,
我看到她跟一个男人在公司大楼外面争执
I saw her arguing with this guy outside the building.
你认得他吗
Did you recognize him?
以前从没见过
I'd never seen him before.
但我听到他在威胁她
But I overheard them, and he was threatening her.
他说她手上有他要的东西
He said she had something he wanted
她必须交出来
and he wouldn't take no for an answer.
-她什么反应  -她说他再来找她的话
- And what was her reaction? - She said she was gonna call the police
就要报警  然后他就气冲冲地走了
if he didn't leave her the hell alone, and then he stormed off.
我问过她是怎么回事
I-I tried to ask her what it was all about,
但她不肯说
but she wouldn't tell me.
你还记得他的样貌  能帮我们做素描画像吗
Do you remember him well enough to help us with a sketch?
应该可以
I think so.
这就是威胁艾拉的人
Okay, this is the guy who threatened Ella.
你相信格蕾丝的说法
So, you believe Grace's story?
她的不在场证明核实了
Well, her alibi checks out.
制服警员还找到两名目击者看到他跟艾拉争执
And UNIS found two witnesses that saw him arguing with Ella.
艾拉美其名是个助手
Ella was basically a glorified assistant.
能有什么是这个男人想要的呢
What could she possibly have had that this man wanted?
你想啊  卡塞尔
Well, think about it, Castle.
玛蒂尔达·金是时尚界最有影响力的人物
Matilda King is the most influential person in fashion,
艾拉跟她又有直接联系
and Ella had direct access to her world.
你是说这个人威胁艾拉
So you're saying this man leveraged Ella
来搞清楚下季裙边的走向
to find out what direction hemlines are going next season?
我刚想到了一个新标题
I just came up with a new title.
"谋杀正当时"
"Murder is the new black."
这话讲得通吗
Does that even make sense?
讲不通  还有件说不通的事
No, it doesn't. And here's something else that doesn't make sense.
你们在艾拉的公寓里
Did you guys find something
-发现了什么吗  -可以这么说
- at Ella's apartment? - You could say that.
我用座机的时候
I went to use the landline,
注意到靠近灯的位置有干扰音
and I noticed some static when I got near a lamp.
把灯拆开之后  瞧我们发现了什么
When we popped that lamp open, look what we found inside.
窃听器
A bug?
为什么有人会窃听艾拉的公寓
Why would someone bug Ella's apartment?
因为她是"尼基塔女郎"
Because... she is "La Femme Nikita",
她在《当代时尚》的工作只是伪装身份
and her job at Modern Fashion is just a cover.
她不是"尼基塔女郎"
She's not "La Femme Nikita."
窃听  来自神秘人的威胁  谋杀
Still, wiretaps, threats from mysterious men, murder --
发生的一切  牵扯到的不止是时尚
Whatever's going on here, it's bigger than fashion.
查查看能不能找到序列号
Okay, see if you can get a serial number.
查出这个窃听器是谁买的
Let's figure out who bought that bug.
好的  非常感谢
All right. Thank you very much.
是科尔多瓦宅邸的活动策划人打来的
That was the event planner at the Cordova House.
他们说秋天还有可预订的日子
They said they still have a few spots open in the fall.
今晚她可以带我们参观一下
She can give us a tour tonight.
那就这么定了
Whoo-hoo! Let's do it.
-水门事件进展如何了  -事情越发复杂了
- So, where are we on watergate? - So, the plot thickens.
艾拉公寓的楼管
The building manager at Ella's apartment
记得一个月前放进去过一个灭虫员
remembers letting an exterminator into her place about a month ago.
通常来说  灭虫员清理虫子[双关]
Usually, exterminators get rid of bugs.
但这位却不然
Only this one didn't.
他所在的公司并不存在
The company that he worked for doesn't exist.
这都是为了什么呢  卡塞尔
I mean, what is this about, Castle?
为什么有人会把艾拉作为目标
Why would someone target Ella?
我说了但你驳回了我的理论
Well, you already heard and rejected my theory.
但你的理论并不能解释
Yeah, but your theory doesn't explain the little detail
蕾妮发现的细节
that Lanie just found out.
艾拉鞋底沾着黑珊瑚
There's black coral on the sole of Ella's shoe,
黑珊瑚不是垃圾箱里的
and it wasn't from the dumpster.
这说不通啊
Well, that doesn't make any sense.
黑珊瑚是热带地区的
Black coral is found in the tropics.
正是如此  这东西怎么会粘到她鞋上
Exactly. So how did this end up on her shoe?
-贝克特  -加上卡塞尔
- Yo, Beckett. - And Castle.
好吧
Sure.
序列号上没有发现
So, no look on the serial number
但对犯罪现场排查后有了重大发现
but we got a hit off the canvass of the crime scene.
一个女裁缝下了夜班后看到街角有个人
A seamstress coming off the late shift saw a guy wait on the corner
就等在艾拉被害的小巷子旁
right near the alley where Ella was killed.
知道他长相了吗
We get a description?
嗯  和画像相符
Yeah, and he matches our sketch.
对  就是他
Yes. That's him.
我路过时
He was standing by the alley
他就站在百老汇咖啡店外的小巷里
outside the broadway coffee shop when I walked by.
那时候几点
And what time was this?
刚过午夜
Just after midnight.
你还记得他多高吗  穿着怎样
Do you recall how tall he was, what he wore?
我就是搞面料的
Fabric is my business.
他穿了件深色西装  高品质羊毛混纺的
He wore a dark suit -- nice quality, wool blend.
还戴了条显眼的条纹领带
Oh, and he had a distinctive striped tie --
深红和深蓝色条纹上有金色三角形交叉
crimson and navy with gold triangles across the stripes.
像是俱乐部的领带
That sounds like a club tie.
深红和深蓝色  我知道那个
Crimson and navy -- yes, I know that one.
金色三角形  那是卡尔顿俱乐部的领带
Gold triangles. That's the Carlton Club tie.
如果我们能把画像
If we can match that
去和他们的会员配对  就能知道他身份了
sketch to one of its members, we got our I.D.
但是那样的俱乐部
Yeah, except clubs like that
出了名地保护会员隐私
are notoriously protective of keeping their members' privacy.
他们不会交出信息的
They're not just gonna hand over that information.
俱乐部不会  但是会员可以
The club won't, no, but one of its members might.
经过艰苦的谈判  和尼克斯队球票的利诱
After a tough negotiation that involved my Knicks tickets
外加我下本书里以他祖母冠名一个角色
and naming a character in my next book after his nana,
我朋友终于给了我这个名字  马库斯·康维
my friend came up with a name -- Marcus Conway.
我们掌握他什么情况
Okay, so, what do we know about him?
他是凯勒曼·古德菲尔德律所的一名律师
He is a lawyer at Kellerman Goodfriend.
那是市里最大的律所之一啊
That's one of the city's biggest law firms.
为什么一个高端律师会对艾拉紧追不放呢
Why is a high-powered lawyer going after Ella?
可能与她的工作有关
Maybe it has to do with her work.
原来马库斯·康维
Turns out that Marcus Conway
是《小妞女装》杂志的总法律顾问
is general counsel for Couture Chick Magazine.
是《时尚女装》  你肯定不知道
That's "Chic", and not that you would know,
但他们是《当代时尚》最强的竞争者
but they are Modern Fashion's biggest competitor.
联系康维的律所  我要知道他在哪
Call Conway's firm. I want to know where he is.
警探  做出这种指控之前
Detective, I would think very carefully
你得仔细考虑一下
before making these kinds of accusations.
康维先生  我没有做出任何指控
Mr. Conway, I am not making any accusations.
我只是简单地陈述事实
I am simply stating fact.
有目击者听到你威胁艾拉·海因斯
We have a witness that heard you threatening Ella Hayes
还有人看到你出现在她被害地点附近
and another one that saw you near where she was killed.
刚好是她遇害的时间
Right about the same time she ended up that way.
你得解释一下
You need to explain yourself.
马库斯  我听说警察来了
Marcus, I heard the police are here.
发生了什么事
What's going on?
你是谁
Who are you?
葛洛丽亚·罗宾斯
Gloria Robins.
我是《时尚女装》的主编
I'm editor-in-chief of Couture Chic.
他们认为我杀了艾拉·海因斯
They think I murdered Ella Hayes.
什么  太荒谬了
What? That's ridiculous.
你知道她是谁
So you know who she is?
-这显然是个大误会  -那就解释清楚
- This is obviously one huge misunderstanding. - Then clear it up.
告诉我你对艾拉·海因斯的了解
Tell me what you know about Ella Hayes.
我们接近艾拉并试图
We approached Ella and attempted to...
将她招入麾下
engage her services.
那就是说你们想雇她
So, basically, you tried to hire her
以获取《当代时尚》的内部信息
to get inside information on Modern Fashion.
-我没那么说  -但她肯定是这么理解的
- I wouldn't put it that way. - Well, I'm pretty sure she would,
所以她拒绝了你
which is why she turned you down.
但是你却不接受拒绝
And you wouldn't take no for an answer.
我们这行竞争很激烈的
Look, this is a competitive business
谁都想抢占先机
with everyone looking to get an edge.
没错  我确实着急想达成交易
Yes, I was aggressive in trying to make a deal,
但我接受了她的拒绝
but when she refused and I accepted that,
再没和她联系
and I never contacted her again.
那你能解释一下在死亡时间前后
Then why were you less than a block away
你恰好在案发现场的事实吗
from where she was killed at about the time she died?
是她给我打的电话
Because she called me.
她昨晚约我见面
She asked me to meet her last night.
为什么
Why would she do that?
可能是因为玛蒂尔达炒了她吧
Probably because matilda just fired her.
总之  她说她有
The bottom line is, she said she had
《当代时尚》的爆炸性内幕
bombshell information on Modern Fashion --
一旦爆料  一定能毁掉《当代时尚》
information that, if it got out, it would destroy the magazine.
康维先生  我查看了艾拉的通话记录
Mr. Conway, I took a look at Ella's cellphone records,
她昨晚没有给你打过电话
she never called you last night.
她打了  我可以证明
She did call, and I can prove it.
她还给我留言了
She left me a message.
我是艾拉
Hey, it's Ella.
你的提议我接受了
I changed my mind about your offer.
我有可以毁掉
I found out something,
《当代时尚》的消息
something that'll ruin Modern Fashion,
让它一败涂地
take down the whole operation.
一小时后百老汇咖啡店见
Meet me at the Broadway coffee shop in an hour.
我等你
I'll see you there.
我等了她两个小时  可她一直没露面
I waited around for two hours, but she never showed.
她掌握了什么信息
What information did she want to share?
我也想知道  可我毫无头绪
Believe me I would love to know, but I have the faintest idea.
你雇她找的是什么消息
What were you trying to hire her to find out?
你也许听说了
As you may have heard,
一个叫格伦·卡特的高科技投资商
a tech-venture capitalist named Glen Carter
上个月买下了《当代时尚》
bought Modern Fashion last month.
格伦计划把玛蒂尔达的宝贝杂志
Glen has big plans to drag Matilda's precious little magazine
带进数码时代
into the digital age.
-计划内容是  -那也是我们想知道的
- Which are? - Well, that's what we wanted to know,
因为我们网站的网上销售没能带来更多营业额
Since our website has failed to generate new subscription business.
所以如果能得到《当代时尚》的新计划
If we could get Modern Fashion's new playbook,
我们就能改进战略  抢占先机
It could help us strategize and stay one step ahead.
所以  你想让艾拉帮忙
So, you wanted to hire Ella
让她告诉你们
so that she could tell you about
《当代时尚》的新方向
the new direction the magazine was taking,
她拒绝了
and when she turned you down,
你们就只说了这些
that was the extent of your contact?
直到她昨晚来电话
Until she called last night.
那窃听器又是怎么回事
And what about the eavesdropping?
你在说什么
W-what are you talking about?
我们在艾拉的公寓找到了一个窃听器
We found a listening device in Ella's apartment.
不是我们干的  与我们无关
That wasn't us. We had nothing to do with that.
这就是我们为什么
So, these records explain why
没找到艾拉和马库斯·康维的通话记录
we missed Ella's phone calls to Marcus Conway.
她是用室友的座机和他联系的
She phoned him using her roommate's landline.
她约康维一小时后在咖啡店见面
So, she told Conway to meet her in the coffee shop in an hour.
她公寓离那儿只有20分钟的路程
It would take her about 20 minutes to get there from her apartment,
她一定是赴约的路上被杀的
So she must have been killed on the way there.
好遗憾
That's a real shame.
瞧瞧她的设计  她其实很有天赋
Looking at her designs, Ella actually had talent.
问题在于  她到底知道了什么
Yeah, well, the question is, what did she know,
凶手杀她是不是为了灭口
and did someone kill her to keep her quiet?
这我不知道
Well, I can't help you out there,
我知道的是  在放置窃听器这事上
but I can tell you that Marcus Conway
马库斯·康维确实是清白的
was telling the truth about not planting that bug.
窃听器的序列号显示它来自皇后区一家叫
Yeah, the serial number led us to a distributor
交替情报的经销商
named Alternate Intelligence in Queens.
他们知道买主是谁吗
Do they know who brought it?
一个月前詹姆斯·卡瓦纳用信用卡
James kavanaugh paid for that listening device
购买了那个窃听器
with a credit card a month ago.
重点在于什么
And when does it get interesting?
在于他不仅是前特种部队成员
When we found out he was former special forces and,
还是现任《当代时尚》的保安队长
not to mention, the head of security at Modern Fashion.
等等  艾拉是被她自己的公司监视了
Wait a minute -- Ella was being spied on by her own magazine?
贝克特  我们约了去看科尔多瓦宅邸的场馆
Oh, Beckett, we have that appointment at the Cordova House.
卡塞尔  抱歉  我有任务在身
Oh, Castle, I'm sorry. Duty calls.
你自己去行吗
Can -- can you go without me
看看是否和照片一样漂亮
and see if it's as good as the pictures?
你信任我的判断吗
You trust me to make this decision on my own?
那还是带上玛莎吧
Can you go with Martha?
我们得传讯詹姆斯·卡瓦纳
We have to bring James Kavanaugh in.
收到
Yeah.
我是保安  当然会有相关设备
I'm in the security business. I buy lots of equipment.
我们在意的是你安装在
Yeah, well, this equipment was a listening device
艾拉·海因斯公寓的那个窃听器
that you installed in Ella Hayes' apartment.
那不是我装的
If you think that, you're mistaken.
是吗  可我们给艾拉公寓的楼管
Really, because we showed your picture
看你的照片后  他指认你就是那个
to the super at Ella's building, and he identified you
进过她公寓的灭虫员
as the exterminator he let into her apartment.
艾拉·海因斯的死和我无关
I had nothing to do with what happened to Ella Hayes.
你擅闯她的房间  安装了窃听器
You broke into her place, you wired it for sound,
现在她死了  还说与你无关
and now she's dead?
詹姆斯
James?
你自己觉得别人会怎么想
Think about how that looks, bro.
你最好把知道的都交代清楚
Your best bet is to tell us exactly what you know.
我只安装了窃听器  没别的了
All I did was bug her place, okay?
格伦·卡特买下杂志之后
I mean, once Glen Carter bought the magazine,
家庭监听就成了惯例
home monitoring got to be a common practice.
这么说是格伦·卡特要求设监听的吗
So, Glen Carter ordered the surveillance?
不  他并不知道这事
No, he didn't know anything about it.
是玛蒂尔达·金要求的
It was ordered by Matilda King.
玛蒂尔达·金
Matilda king.
-你确定吗  -当然  千真万确
- You sure about that? - Yes, I'm sure.
她害怕有人要抢了她的饭碗
She got all freaked out about someone coming after her job,
所以她说再也不知道该相信谁
so she said she didn't know who she could trust anymore.
好  那谁负责监听艾拉的公寓呢
Okay, so, who monitored the audio from Ella's apartment?
玛蒂尔达让我装好设备
Matilda had me set it up
所有音频都直接传到她的电脑
so that it fed directly to her computer.
你知道这说明什么吗
You realize what this means?
艾拉用座机打给马库斯·康维
Ella called Marcus Conway on the landline,
说她能击垮《当代时尚》
told him she could take down the magazine,
而这些话都被玛蒂尔达听到了
and Matilda heard the whole thing.
好的  非常感谢
Okay. Thank you very much.
《当代时尚》大楼的大堂保安
So, the guard in the lobby of the Modern Fashion building
看到玛蒂尔达昨晚11点30离开
saw Matilda leave there last night at 11:30,
她走得很匆忙
and she was in a big hurry.
11点30么
11:30?
正好是艾拉打电话给马库斯·康维之后
Well, that's right after Ella called Marcus Conway.
玛蒂尔达知道艾拉要去告密
Matilda knew that Ella was about to spill the beans
击垮《当代时尚》
and bring down the magazine.
于是玛蒂尔达去阻止她了
So Matilda went to stop her.
她就是凶手
She's our killer.
等等等等  她正在打电话
Wait, wait, wait. She's on a call.
她可以回电
She can call back.
格伦  这杂志并不只是推特转发或脸书点赞
Glen, this magazine is not about tweets or likes on facebook,
我的天呐
for god's sake!
57年来
For 57 years,
女性买这本杂志都是为了时尚
women have been purchasing this magazine for the fashion!
玛蒂尔达  冷静
Matilda, please.
她们工作不顺心  生活不如意时
Whenever they've had a bad day at work or at home,
她们想到的总是我们
they've come to us!
我们让她们逃脱现实  给她们梦幻
We are their escape! We are their fantasy!
把七零八落的生活拼凑起来的是时装
It's the clothing that stitches it all together.
这才是最重要的
That's what matters.
-没什么可说了  -格伦
- We're done here. - Glen!
格伦
Glen!
抱歉  没看到你在那
Oh. I'm sorry. I didn't see you there.
金女士  你脾气不小啊
You've got a hell of a temper, Ms. King.
这不是脾气
It's not temper.
这是挫败
It's frustration.
我们的新老板格伦·卡特
Glen Carter, our new owner,
关心的不是时尚而是金钱
cares more about money than fashion.
就因为这个  所以你疑心他会把你换掉吗
Is that why you were paranoid he was gonna replace you?
我不知道你听说了什么  但我可是玛蒂尔达·金
I don't know what you've heard, but I'm Matilda King.
我代表这本杂志
My name is synonymous with this magazine.
他不敢把我换掉的
He wouldn't dare replace me.
那为什么他买下杂志的时候
So then why did you order the monitoring
你要下令监听
of all of your employees' conversations
你员工的所有对话呢
the moment that he bought the magazine?
确实瞒不过你
You are quite the detective.
请坐
Take a seat.
从杂志被收购开始  谣言便四起
Yes, since the purchase, rumors have been swirling.
我也想单纯认为它们只是谣言
I'd like to think that they're just rumors,
但我冒不起险
but I can't afford to take that chance.
我得确认我的手下绝对忠诚
I need to know my people are loyal.
通过窃听他们住所吗
By bugging their homes?
是经过他们许可的
With their permission.
我们曾有过类似状况发生
We've had some loyalty issues,
所以我的律师们在雇佣协议上
so my lawyers added some fine print
增添了些附属细则
to their employment agreements.
你真的认为这样就能在法庭上脱罪吗
Do you actually believe that's gonna fly in court?
我的律师们是这样想的
My lawyers seem to think so.
告诉我  这些和你的调查有什么关系
Now, what does this have to do with your investigation?
鉴于你要被换掉的谣言
Look, given the rumors about your job,
当你发现艾拉把不利于《当代时尚》的情报带给对手后
it must have been disconcerting to find out Ella
一定非常不安吧
was taking damaging information on Modern Fashion to the competition.
你指的是什么
To what are you referring? What information?
我们还不清楚
We don't know that.
我们只知道就在她安排好
But what we do know is moments after she made the arrangements
要卖出那份情报后
to sell that information,
有人看到你跑出去
you were seen running out of here.
你认为我跑出去是去谋杀艾拉吗
You think that I ran out of here to kill Ella?
你的安全主管说你下令安装监听设备
Your head of security says that you're set up
是要在你的电脑上即时听到录音
to listen to these recordings live on your computer.
我到周末才听
Something I do on the weekend.
平日里要管理杂志  事务繁忙
I'm a little busy running a magazine during the week.
对  这职位你急切地想要保住
Yeah, a position that you're desperate to defend.
这就是作案动机和作案时机
That's motive and that's opportunity.
我昨晚跑出办公室
I ran out of my office last night
因为我约好和奥斯卡·德拉伦塔喝一杯  要迟到了
because I was late for drinks with Oscar de la Renta.
你尽可以去核实
Feel free to check.
至于艾拉对杂志的威胁
Regarding Ella's threat to the magazine,
我从没听过她这么说
I never heard her say that.
那你也不知道她掌握了什么情报吗
And you have no idea what Ella was taking to the competition?
不清楚
None.
但如果你查出来了  我还是有兴趣知道的
But if you find out, I'd be curious to know.
还有什么事吗  探长
Anything else, detective?
我需要那些录音
I'm gonna need those recordings.
贝克特  玛蒂尔达的不在场证明确认了
Hey, Beckett. Matilda's alibi checks out.
她凌晨两点前都在和奥斯卡喝酒
She was having drinks with Oscar until about 2:00 a.m.
所以玛蒂尔达不是凶手
So Matilda's not our killer?
而我们还不知道艾拉带到竞争对手去的
And we still don't know what explosive information
爆炸性的情报是什么
Ella was taking to the competition.
我在这些音频里的发现
I think I may have found something on these audio files
可以帮你们把这件事弄清楚
that might shed light on that.
我一直在听近一星期
So I have been going though about a week of
艾拉和她室友间的无聊对话
inane conversations between Ella and her roommate.
她在被杀当晚打了一通电话
But she did place a call on the day of the murder
非常奇怪
that was pretty strange.
听听看
Check it out.
嗨  我是艾拉
Hey. It's me -- Ella.
《当代时尚》内部发生了奇怪的事
Something weird is going on inside Modern Fashion.
我觉得有人在针对我
I think someone's targeting me.
我需要你的帮助  赶快回电
I need your help. Call me back.
我们知道她这是打给谁吗
Do we know who's on the other end of that call?
根据这些座机的通话记录
Based on the landline phone records,
这通电话是打给《当代时尚》的一个人
the call was placed to someone at Modern Fashion,
但因为线路经由电话总机
But it was routed through a switchboard,
所以无法显示她是打给谁的
so it doesn't show who she was connected to.
这范围可大到在那工作的100多个人
This directory lists over 100 people that work there.
可不是
Yeah.
幸运的是我有顺风耳
Lucky I have crazy-good hearing.
再听听开头
Listen to the beginning again.
我让个技术员分析了这些哔声
I had a tech analyze those beeps
然后将它们联系到相应的数字
And connect them to the corresponding digits.
这通电话是打给这个电话分机
The call was placed to this extension.
阿曼多·蒙托亚
Armando Montoya.
-他是《当代时尚》里的网络技术员  -是的
- He's an I.T. tech at modern fashion? - Mm-hmm.
艾拉为什么要向他求助
What was Ella doing calling him for help?
我们是朋友
We were friends, you know?
这里的人都当我是空气  但艾拉没有
To most of the people here, I'm invisible, but Ella saw me.
她人很好
She was nice.
她死的那天为什么需要你的帮助
Why did she need your help the day she died?
她想让我看看玛蒂尔达的日程表
She wanted me to look at Matilda's calendar.
为什么
What for?
因为玛蒂尔达错过了一些重要的会议
Because Matilda missed some important meetings,
但是艾拉非常确定她把会议
But Ella was sure she entered them
都输入到日程表里去了
into the calendar correctly.
她想知道日程表是否被篡改了
She wanted to know if the calendar had been tampered with.
那到底是不是呢
And -- and was it?
过去几周  有几处日程被篡改了
Yes, everal entries had been changed over the past couple weeks --
都是在半夜发生的
All in the middle of the night.
当我给她看的时候
When I showed it to her,
她确信有人想陷害她
She was convinced that someone was trying to set her up.
你知道是谁改的吗
Well, were you able to tell who made those changes?
不知道  我只发现IP地址不在杂志内部
No, I tracked them all to an I.P. address outside Modern Fashion.
我只能做到这一步
It's the best I could do.
我告诉她后
I give her the info
她说她要找出陷害她的人
and she said she was gonna figure out who set her up...
让他们付出代价
and make them pay.
再听到她的消息时  她已经死了
Next I hear, she's dead.
你还有那个IP地址吗
Do you still have that I.P. Address?
知道了  我会让技术员查查的
Yeah. Okay. I'll have a tech run it down.
但为什么会有人想陷害一个时尚助理呢
But why would anyone want to sabotage a fashion assistant?
我不知道  埃斯波
I don't know, Espo.
如果艾拉在追查幕后主使  也许她找到了
If Ella went after whoever's behind this, maybe she found one.
如果我查到地址  给你打电话
All right, well, I'll give you a call when I get a location.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
还有问题吗  警探
More questions, detective?
事实上  我们有证据表明
Actually, we found evidence that suggests
不是艾拉搞砸了你的会议
Ella wasn't responsible for screwing up your appointments.
有人篡改了你的日程表
Someone else changed your calendar --
办公室之外的人干的
Someone outside of this office.
你是说我无缘无故把艾拉炒了
Are you saying that I fired Ella for no reason?
你知道为什么有人会这样对她吗
Do you know why someone would have done this to her?
不知道
No.
但我知道为什么有人会这样对我
But I do know why someone would want to do this to me.
什么意思
What do you mean?
自从格伦·卡特买下《当代时尚》
Ever since Glen Carter bought modern fashion,
那些鲨鱼就游过来了  他们闻到了血腥味
The sharks have been circling. They smell blood.
所以日程错误会在这个重要时期影响你的形象
So the calendar mistakes made you look bad at a critical time?
等我一下
Excuse me.
这正是我需要的  太"好"了
Oh, this is just what I need.
发生什么事了
What's wrong?
我要在半个小时内定夺一条要在这期上杂志的裙子
I have to make a decision in the next half-hour about a dress,
可模特还没出现
this issue, and the model didn't show up.
贝克特警探
Detective Beckett.
几年前我给你一份工作时  你拒绝了我
You said "No" to me years ago when I offered you a job.
现在还我一个人情吧
Might you do a little favor for me now?
理查德  看看这些漂亮的古董吊灯
Oh, Richard, look at these beautiful antique chandeliers.
如果你们感兴趣的话
So, if you're interested,
明年秋天还有两个时段可以预定
I have a couple of slots for fall 2015 still open.
等等  你是说明年秋天吗
Excuse me. Did you say "Fall 2015"?
没错
That's correct.
当我们在电话里讲的时候
When we spoke on the phone,
我以为  我们是在说  今年秋天
I thought...we were speaking of...this fall.
不可能的  几个月前就被预定了
No way. That's been booked for months.
抱歉  但我得接这通电话
Uh, excuse me, but I have to take this call.
到处看看  我马上回来
Look around, and I'll be right back.
这的确是个漂亮的礼堂
Ugh. Well, it is a beautiful venue.
要等太长时间了
And it's a long time to wait.
是啊  不过准备时间也变长了
Yeah, and a long time to plan.
我只是感觉我等得够久了  妈妈
I just feel like I've waited long enough, mother.
我不想在我们再进一步之前
I-I don't want to waste any more time
浪费任何时间了
before we take the next step.
那就不要等了  我相信还会有
Then don't. I'm sure there's another venue out there
你俩都喜欢的礼堂的
that the two of you will just fall in love with.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧
Okay.
这样的事从来没发生过
This never happens,
弗里德曼夫妇刚刚取消了他们的婚礼
but the Friedmans just called off their wedding,
这下我们春季就有了空位
and we now have an opening for spring.
2016年的春季
Spring...2016?
不  今年春季
No, this spring.
我手里有很多夫妇
Uh, I have a long list of couples
会不顾一切抢下这个空档的
that would snatch this up immediately,
不过既然你们就在这
but since you're here...
你需要帮忙吗
Do you need any help in there?
不用
No.
我之前答应帮你试穿一套礼服的时候
You know what, when you asked me to try on a dress and I said yes,
完全没有想到会是这样一套礼服
I had no idea it was gonna be this kind of a dress.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
真漂亮
It's amazing.
是吗
Yeah?
瞧瞧这些刺绣
The embroidery.
还有奥地利水晶
And the Austrian crystal.
这真是  真是美妙极了
It's just -- just heavenly.
可不是吗
Yeah. It is, isn't it?
来
Come.
这个也许
Well, t-this probably would have
也许那个没来的模特穿起来更好看
looked better on the model that didn't show up.
不  别傻了  你穿着很完美
No, don't be silly. It's perfect on you.
相信我  我可是这方面专家
Trust me. I'm an expert.
假如我有个女儿
In fact, if I had a daughter,
我也希望她能穿上这样的礼服
this is exactly the kind of dress I would want for her.
你会是一个美丽无比的新娘
You are gonna make a beautiful bride someday.
谢谢
Thank you.
玛蒂尔达  会议室的配饰展示已经准备好了
Matilda, we're ready for the accessories spread in the conference room.
失陪一下  五分钟后回来
Excuse me. I'll be back in five minutes.
礼堂怎么样
How's the venue?
棒极了  简直富丽堂皇
Amazing. Yeah, so amazing.
虽然之前他们要到2015年秋才有空位
And they didn't have any spots open until fall of 2015,
不过后来有一对分手了
but a couple just broke up.
他们的不幸成就了我们一生的喜悦
And their unfortunate misery can be our lifelong joy.
我们可以拿下他们今春的空档
We can take their spot for the spring.
春天
The spring.
是的  还有很多夫妇也想要
I know. And there's a lot of couples who want it.
但如果我能在今晚交上押金
But if I put down a deposit tonight,
这就是我们的了
it's ours.
你觉得怎样
So, what do you say?
贝克特  还在吗
Beckett, are you there?
在的
Yeah.
可我以为我们一致觉得那个礼堂很棒
Okay, but I-I thought we agreed that the venue was amazing.
是的  只是我想到还有好多事情要做
Yeah, we did. It's just I started thinking about the details
还要仔细筹备安排
and the planning that we have to do, and I just --
我不想太着急做这些
I don't want to rush any of this.
如果你决定了  那就这样
Okay. If you're sure that's it.
就这样吧
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
我们会找到另一个礼堂的  卡塞尔
I -- I mean, we're gonna find another venue, Castle.
也一样富丽堂皇
It's gonna be great.
如果
Look, if any --
我们一个技术人员追踪到了那个IP地址
So, a tech was able to track down that I.P. address.
更改日程表的人
Whoever changed that calendar
是索霍区的一个设计工作室的
did it from a design studio in SoHo.
《当代时尚》和这个工作室有什么关联吗
Is there any connection between the studio and Modern Fashion?
事实上  他们有关系
As a matter of fact, there is.
这家工作室属于一个被《当代时尚》
It belongs to one of the designers being featured
"美妙五人"栏目收录的一位设计师
in Modern Fashion's "Fab Five" Spread.
优美
Yumi.
姓什么
Yumi what?
就叫优美
Just Yumi.
我猜如果没有姓  你可以收更多的钱
I guess if you don't have a last name, you can charge more.
那为什么他或者他工作室的某人
So, why would he or someone from his studio
会想要篡改玛蒂尔达的日程表呢
be changing Matilda's calendar?
我不知道  不过我知道的是
I don't know, but I can tell you this.
艾拉被害当晚去过那个工作室
It looks like Ella may have been there the night she was killed.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
优美的网站
Yumi's website.
该工作室当季的设计主题是
The current design line being produced at his studio
有珊瑚装饰的晚礼服
features dresses embellished with coral,
除了这个模特非常性感之外
And, in addition to the fact that this model is hot,
她身上穿的黑珊瑚
she's wearing black coral.
和蕾妮在艾拉鞋底发现的
The same kind of coral that Lanie found
是同一种珊瑚
stuck to the bottom of Ella's shoe.
我们走
Let's go.
我可能会把她叫来接受询问
I'm probably gonna have to call her in for an interrogation.
不  亲爱的
No, sweetie.
你去和那个大小姐说
You tell little miss all that
优美说这里只有一个女王
Yumi says there's only one diva in this room.
如果她不想穿那双粉色Louboutins
If she doesn't want to wear the pink Louboutins,
那她就别想参加这个秀
she is out of the show.
现在的模特
Models.
节食让她们变得越来越令人烦心
The lack of food makes them so very fraught.
-优美先生  -叫我优美就行
- Uh, Mr. Yumi. - Please, just Yumi.
优美
Okay. Yumi.
你最后一次见到艾拉·海因斯是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Ella Hayes?
艾拉·海因斯
Ella Hayes?
玛蒂尔达的助理  被杀害的那个女孩
Matilda's assistant -- the girl who was killed?
是她啊
Yes, of course.
我们有证据表明她昨晚在这里
Well, we have reason to believe that she was here last night.
是的  她在这里
Yes, she was.
她来这里做什么
Why was she here?
她想我给她一份工作
She, uh, she came to ask me for a job.
真的
Really?
我告诉她我很想帮她
I told her I wanted to help,
但这件事我无能为力
but there was absolutely nothing I could do.
被玛蒂尔达·金炒了鱿鱼的人  没人敢雇他们
When Matilda King fires someone, they are radioactive.
你知道她为什么被解雇吗
Do you have any idea why she was fired?
不知道
No.
我觉得你知道
I think you do.
有人篡改了玛蒂尔达·金的日程表
Someone changed Matilda King's calendar.
玛蒂尔达以为是艾拉  但其实不是她
Matilda thought it was Ella, but it wasn't Ella.
是你工作室的人干的
It was someone from your studio.
我们追踪到了IP地址  艾拉也追踪到了
We traced the I.P. address, so did Ella.
所以她昨晚才会来到这里
That's what she was doing here last night.
她不是来向你要份工作
She wasn't asking for a job.
她是来找出是谁篡改了日程表
She was looking to find who made those changes --
是谁毁了她的事业
Who ruined her career.
鉴于你刚刚对我们撒谎了
And given the fact that you just lied to us,
我猜就是你干的
I am guessing it was you.
我
Me?
你们知道玛蒂尔达·金在时装产业
Do you have any idea how powerful Matilda King is
有多强大的影响力吗
in the fashion industry?
我的设计是"美妙五人"的得奖作品
My design is a "Fab Five" winner.
玛蒂尔达就要让我名声鹊起
Matilda's about to make me famous.
惹了她等于自断前程
Messing with her would be career suicide.
我怎么可能有杀人动机呢
What could possibly be my motive?
很简单
Oh, it's simple.
你要让她被解雇
You needed to get her fired.
你要诋毁她的名声
You needed to discredit her.
我究竟为什么要这么做
Why on earth would I do that?
因为你在"美妙五人"的得奖设计
Because your winning "Fab Five" design...
不是出自你之手
isn't yours.
这是艾拉的素描本
From Ella's sketchbook.
与图片上的一模一样
They're exactly the same.
艾拉是个有理想抱负的设计师
Ella was an aspiring designer.
她肯定是模仿我的设计
She must have copied me.
不  艾拉的舍友一个月前已经看到在她绘图了
No. Ella's roommate saw her making those sketches months ago.
这么说
Okay, then.
如果这是出自她的素描本
If you found it in her sketchbook,
那怎么会在我手上呢
then how did I get it?
玛蒂尔达的另一个助理格蕾丝
Well, Matilda's other assistant, Grace,
已经确认了她看见艾拉给你她的复印本
confirmed seeing Ella give you copies of her sketches.
很显然  当你去"美妙五人"的展示会议上
Apparently, you had them on you
你就将它据为己有了
when you went in on your "Fab five" pitch meeting.
从那开始  你就自编自导自演了
And from there, the story writes itself.
你展示了自己的设计作品
You showed your designs,
然而你的作品不够好
and they just weren't good enough to make the cut,
但是艺术总监在你的包里看到了这些
but then the artistic director sees these in your bag --
这设计新奇  惊艳  蕴玉之石
The fresh, stunning, raw talent --
"美妙五人"的不二之选
Perfect for the "Fab Five."
只是这不是你的作品
Except they weren't your designs.
这事只有两个人知道  你和艾拉
Only two people knew that -- you and Ella.
成为"美妙五人"设计师
And being a "Fab Five" designer
可以成就你的事业  所以你做出了决定
could literally make your career, so you made a choise.
一旦你被选为"美妙五人"之后
Once you were chosen for the "Fab Five,"
你意识到艾拉会知道你偷了她的设计
you realized that Ella would know you had stolen her designs.
你得去破坏她的名声让全世界都不相信她
You had to discredit her so that no one would believe her.
我要请律师
I want a lawyer.
艾拉肯定在工作室和优美当面对质过
Ella must have confronted Yumi at his studio.
如果她威胁要曝光丑闻
If she threatened to expose the whole scandal,
他的职业生涯就完蛋了
his career would be over.
他必须杀了她掩盖事实
He had to kill her to hide the truth.
没错  这就都说得通了
Yeah. That all makes sense.
现在我们只要把他和案发现场联系起来就行
Now we just have to connect him to the crime scene.
可现在的问题是  联系不起来
Only one problem -- you can't.
优美没杀害艾拉
Yumi didn't kill Ella.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
多个员工见到艾拉和优美对质
Multiple employees saw Ella confront Yumi,
但她走了之后
but after she took off,
他一直待在工作室直到凌晨三点  没离开过
he was at the studio till 3:00 a.m. He never left.
等等  你确定吗
Wait. Are you -- are you sure?
他的不在场证明确认了
His alibi rocks out.
但我们知道工作室里
but we know someone changed matilda's calendar
有人篡改了玛蒂尔达的日程表
from that studio.
他肯定以某种方式牵涉其中
He has to be involved somehow.
我觉得其他人也牵涉到了
I think someone else was, too.
我查过了优美的通话记录
I went through Yumi's phone records,
艾拉离开之后
and after Ella left,
他打了六个电话到《当代时尚》去
he made half a dozen phone calls to Modern Fashion.
如此漂亮的设计
Such beautiful designs.
这么长时间  我竟然不知道
After all this time, I had no idea.
如果她知道这些设计被偷了
If she knew these designs had been stolen,
为什么不来找我
why didn't she come to me.
也许她觉得你根本不会听她的话
Maybe she didn't think you would listen --
至少不会听像她这样的人说话
At least, not to someone like her.
也许她只是想报复
Maybe she just wanted revenge.
那样的话她目的达到了
She would've gotten it.
如果我们的"美妙五人"名单被《时尚女装》曝光是舞弊的话
If Couture Chic xposed that our"Fab five" list was corrupt,
我就会丢了饭碗
it would have cost me my job.
还会给谁带来损失
Who else stood to lose?
所有牵涉其中的人
Everyone involved, I suppose.
艾拉离开优美的工作室之后
Well, just after Ella left Yumi's studio,
他打了一连串的电话
he made a series of phone calls
给《当代时尚》的某个人
to someone here at modern fashion.
这个人知道优美的秘密
Someone who must have known Yumi's secret --
帮他掩盖事实真相
who was helping him cover it up.
这个人知道如果真相大白了
Someone who knew that if the truth got out,
就会同时毁了他们两个
it could destroy them both.
只有一个人会这么做
There's only one person it could be.
谁
Who?
这期杂志一周内就要印刷了
We go to print in one week on this issue,
可是你们给我的封面备选还是不尽人意
and I'm still not happy with the cover options.
而且我们"美妙五人"栏目也还没完成
And we're still not there with the "Fab Five" spread!
散会吧  继续干活去
Now, go, please, make it better!
朱利安  聊一下
Julian, a word.
当你见到优美交上来的设计时
What was your first reaction
你的第一反应是什么
when you saw Yumi's design submission?
我惊呆了
Blown away.
所以我才提名他
I mean, that's why I nominated him.
那你能不能告诉我  当他向你坦白
Now, is there a reason why you didn't come to me
他偷了艾拉的设计时
and tell me when he confessed to you
你为什么没来告诉我呢
that he stole Ella's design?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我今早跟优美谈过
I had a word with Yumi this morning.
他说这件事你早就知情了
He told me you've known for a while.
而且他还说篡改我的日程表是你的主意
And he also said it was your idea to change my calendar.
他在撒谎
He's lying.
然后我又问过卡特先生
Then I spoke to Mr. Carter,
他证实了我的猜测
and he confirmed my suspicion.
你对我的职位虎视眈眈
You've been gunning for my job.
-这又能证明什么  -证明你想一石二鸟
- What does that prove? - It proves that you tried to kill two birds with one stone.
你篡改我的日程表  败坏艾拉的名声也伤到了我
You changed my calendar in order to discredit Ella and undermine me.
-你不知道自己在说什么  -少来这套
- You don't know what you're talking about. - Don't even.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
我离开这  都用不着到今晚  就能在任何一间
I can walk out of here and get hired at any magazine I want
杂志社找到工作
by the end of the day.
你短期内都不用再找工作了  朱利安
You won't be applying for a new job anytime soon, Julian.
天啊
Oh, my...
这太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
玛蒂尔达·金
Matilda King --
她最喜欢这样折磨人玩了
she takes pleasure in torturing people like this.
实际上  她给你们讲的故事就跟她本人一样疯狂
Fact is, her story is as crazy as she is.
只不过我们搜了你家附近的垃圾桶
Except we searched the dumpsters around your apartment,
找到了艾拉的围巾
and we found Ella's scarf --
也正是那条你用来勒死她的围巾
the one that you used to strangle her.
实验室在那条围巾上找到了两组DNA
The lab also found two sets of DNA on that scarf --
艾拉的和你的
Ella's and yours.
在我的律师到之前  我都不会再说一句话
I'm not gonna say another word until my lawyer's present.
检察官怎么说
So, what did the D.A. say?
朱利安不肯认罪  他要在庭审上碰碰运气
That Julian's gonna plead not guilty, take his chances at trial.
好消息是优美决定和检方合作换取免罪
The good news is Yumi cut a deal to avoid charges.
看来谋杀不是他的菜
I guess murder is not his type of accessory.
他向检察官交代  他告诉过朱利安
Yeah. He confessed to telling Julian
艾拉已经发现了真相  朱利安说他会摆平她
that Ella figured it all out and Julian told him that he would take care of her.
看来今年"美妙五人"变成"美妙四人"了
So, I guess the "Fab Five" is gonna be "Fab Four" this year.
我一直以为时尚产业很光彩迷人呢
I always thought the fashion industry seemed glamorous.
没想到就连黑帮都比他们有道德
Turns out, mobsters are more ethical.
天啊  不然你认为我为什么要退出那行呀
Oh, my gosh. Why do you think I quit?
我宁可跟杀人犯混在一块也不要天天对着一堆模特
I'll take murderers over models any day.
要是杀人犯都这么性感就好了
If only murderers were this hot.
我还有些文书工作没做完
I got a bit of paperwork to do.
无聊的文书工作
Ah! Boring paperwork.
我听到这句话就想回家了
That is my cue to leave.
-晚点见  -好的  我做完就去找你
- I'll see you later? - Yeah. Yeah, I'll see you when I'm done.
要来杯酒吗
Hey. Shall I pour you a glass?
不  现在不喝
Uh, no. Not right now.
一切都还好吗
Everything all right?
宝贝  咱俩得聊聊
Babe, we have to talk.
通常人们在宣布坏消息之前才用这个开场白
Wow. That's something people say before they deliver bad news.
你还记得你昨晚打电话问我场地的事吗
You know when you called last night about the venue?
我当时跟玛蒂尔达在一起  她希望我试一条裙子
I was with Matilda, and she wanted me to model a dress.
那条裙子是件婚纱
And it was a wedding dress.
当我看到自己穿着婚纱的样子  我就
And when I saw myself in it, I just --
我想起了我母亲
I started to think about my mom.
她一定希望自己能参与这一切
She would have loved to have been a part of all of this,
帮我选婚礼上用的花  陪我试婚纱
to help pick out the flowers and try on the dresses and...
当我在镜子里看到自己  我就
When I looked at myself in the mirror, I just --
我期待见到她站在我身后
I-I halfway expected to see her right behind me...
可她却不在  有那么一刻  我心里想
And she wasn't there. And, just for a moment, I thought to myself,
"我不知道没有她在  我能不能完成这一切"
"I don't know if I can do all of this without her."
所以当你问的时候  我才没答应
And that's why I said no when you asked about the venue.
很抱歉  是我在犯傻
I'm so sorry. It was so stupid.
不
No.
不  一点都不傻
No, not stupid.
这是人性
Human.
你知道我还希望她能见证什么吗
Do you know what else I wish she could experience?
你
You.
真的吗
Really?
她肯定会超爱你
She would have loved you.
凯特
You know, Kate...
如果你还需要多点时间的话
if you need more time --
不不  我不需要更多时间考虑了
No. No, I don't -- I don't need any more time.
我甚至不想等到秋天
I don't even want us to wait until the fall.
我觉得我们可以找到另外一个能在春天结婚的地方
I think we can find a new venue in the spring.
你觉得咱们能做得到
You think we can pull it off?
当然
Yeah.
我婚纱都准备好了
I mean, I already have the dress.